Pratyush Mangalam

Bangalore -560103 | 9738920061 | pratyush.or.mangalam@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/pratyush-mangalam-39052213a/

Professional Summary

Successful Backend Developer offering 4+ years of experience in demanding environments focused on producing cutting- edge systems. Skilled in directing development with creative and performance-oriented approach. Innovator with deep knowledge in latest industry trends and advancement.

Skills & Abilities

- · Python
- · Django and Django REST Framework
- · AWS for architecture design
- · Golang

- Relational Database (RDS, Postgres), No SQL DB(MongoDB), Redis, Timeseries DB
- · Docker, GIT, Jenkins
- · Airflow, Celery, Luigi

Experience

Software Engineer | Open Financial Technology | 09/2022 - 04/2023

- $\cdot\;$ Developed microservice using Golang and Gorm for reporting service for open money products.
- · Created a fund transfer microservice architecture and developed it using Golang for different banks.
- · Implemented Airflow for existing cron jobs and led and educated other teams to use the Airflow tool.
- Developed Bulk transfer service using Airflow which reduced bulk transfer time to 50%.

Software Engineer | Cult Fit | 09/2021 - 09/2022

- Designed server-side architecture and implemented cloud-based back-end solutions from scratch for the company's first product in the market, the CULTBIKE-exercise bike that allows live and on-demand streamed workouts with the best trainers.
- · Worked on storing and analysing real-time sensor data into time series database service for IoT and operational applications.
- Defined and conducted design processes at all stages, including research, conceptualization, testing, and implementation.
- · Resolved scalability problems and addressed security concerns.

Associate Software Engineer | Iquanti | 02/2019 - 09/2021

- · Worked as a back-end engineer for the product ALPS- an enterprise SEO Tool designed with micro service architecture, used for optimizing the site around effective keywords that drive relevant traffic to maximize conversion, powered by an analytics-driven keyword prioritization engine.
- Designed and developed the data-on demand, an exclusive feature to bring in the SERP data for given keywords.
- · Worked on the feature to enhance the data accuracy, designing proper object-oriented modules for data collection and pre-processing.
- · Worked on the orchestrator layer, implemented using LUIGI, helping build complex pipelines of batch jobs.
- Made the manual task into an automated system to speed up the process and improve the experience of granting access to the user for the product using Django model.

Education

Computer Science | The NIE | Mysore